Daniel Tolczyk

Starting my technical career in the United States Marine Corp as a Cryptologic Linguist, I fell in love with technology. After my enlistment I worked in physical security and decided to combine my passion for technology and security into a career. I attended university for a BS in Cybersecurity and Information Assurance. During this time I also attended a coding bootcamp for veterans called Code Platoon. Through this program I was able to compete for an internship and was accepted as an intern at Motorola Solutions where I began initially as an Applications Programmer and later promoted into an Information Security Specialist in line with my goals and education.

Chicago,IL daniel.tolczyk@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Motorola Solutions — Information Security Specialist

June 2020 - PRESENT

- Primary cybersecurity expert acting as a liaison between multiple product teams and cybersecurity teams.
- Participated in Secure Design Reviews and auditing of STIG requirements for 2 product releases.
- Managed the scanning and tracking of third-party open-source software using Mend, Tenable, OWASP ZAP, and manual internal tools
- Responsible for the creation and maintenance of customer-facing documentation regarding software versioning and open-source licenses.
- Configured logging to meet cybersecurity requirements for multiple back-end components.
- Wrote and updated scripts to manage the creation of administrative accounts.

Spirit Inc — Cloud Security Analyst

May 2019 - August 2019

- Conducted Risk Assessment's in preparation for SOC2 audits.
- Implemented initial security program by creating new security and backup plan policies.
- Identified and responded to minor security incidents with remediation through personally training employees on solutions.

Park Tower Senior Housing, LP— IT Specialist and User Technical Support

May 2018 - May 2019

• Upgraded and maintained computer security on systems used to access sensitive personal information.

SKILLS

Vulnerability Management
Vulnerability Detection
Tenable Nessus
Jira and Confluence
Team Management

Certifications

ISC2- SSCP: This certificate demonstrates my advanced technical skills and knowledge to implement, monitor and administer IT infrastructure using security best practices.

CompTIA- Pentest+: This certificate demonstrates my ability to build and plan comprehensive vulnerability assessments and manage security with a heavy focus on compliance.

CompTIA- CySA+: This certificate demonstrates my ability to leverage intelligence and threat detection techniques, identify and address vulnerabilities and

- Improved computer performance, maintaining programs and skills needed for life-betterment and support of clientele.
- Led training on software, web applications, and security weekly for residents.

United States Marine Corps — Middle Eastern Cryptologic Linguist

September 2004 - November 2009

- Monitored, transcribed, and translated intercepted target communications.
- Performed analysis and exploitation of designated foreign communications.
- Installed, operated, and performed preventive maintenance of intercept equipment.

works towards being proactive with capturing and monitoring of network traffic findings.

CompTIA - Security+: This certificate demonstrates my ability to create access controls and identity management, write compliance and operational security documents and find threats and vulnerabilities within a company's network.

EDUCATION

Westerns Governors University — B.S Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

2019 -2021

WGU's B.S of Cybersecurity and Information Assurance degree reinforced and taught the following. Data management, web and cloud security, secure system design and hacking countermeasures.

Code Platoon — Full Stack Web Development

2020 -2020

A bootcamp made for veterans, I studied full stack development. I learned python and javascript with PostgreSQL, git and Github. This has allowed me to understand SSDLC and build robust security plans for software engineering.

${\bf Spokane\ Falls\ Community\ College-} Associates\ of\ Arts$

2016 -2018

To further my education and build a career I spent time gaining an Associate of arts, I took additional classes to earn my degree. Those classes are the following. Linux, Network Management, IT Ethics, Network security, Ethical Hacking, Endpoint security and Project Management.

LANGUAGES

Arabic